<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Random | Joshua Kalpin's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kapin.github.io/blog/categories/random/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kapin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2013-11-08T23:58:00-08:00</updated>
  <id>http://kapin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joshua Kalpin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blog All the Things!]]></title>
    <link href="http://kapin.github.io/blog/2013/11/08/blog-all-the-things/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-08T22:54:00-08:00</updated>
    <id>http://kapin.github.io/blog/2013/11/08/blog-all-the-things</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well this is a long time coming to say the least. I&rsquo;ve kept saying that I&rsquo;m going to build my website since I started
at UW and well it is finally here.</p>

<p>This website is built with the magic that is known as <a href="http://octopress.org">Octopress</a> using the awesome <a href="https://github.com/alexgaribay/octoflat">Octoflat</a> theme.
I&rsquo;ve tweaked a few things from the default theme and will hopefully change the colours around in the future to be a little less bright, but I&rsquo;m incredibly happy that it is finally done.</p>

<h2>Why Octopress?</h2>

<p>First, I didn&rsquo;t want to deal with the pain of setting up a hosting server to run a simple website. Octopress is built on top of Jekyll, a static page generator.
This allows me to write everything here in markdown, which is then converted into HTML when I deploy. Speaking of deploying, it is just as simple.</p>

<p><div class='bogus-wrapper'><notextile><figure class='code'><figcaption><span>Deploying Octopress </span></figcaption>
<div class="highlight"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre class="line-numbers"><span class='line-number'>1</span>
<span class='line-number'>2</span>
</pre></td><td class='code'><pre><code class=''><span class='line'>rake generate
</span><span class='line'>rake deploy</span></code></pre></td></tr></table></div></figure></notextile></div></p>

<p>Lastly, the big thing that drew me to it was the vast array of themes and plugins. I&rsquo;m not a designer nor do I really enjoy digging around in vast piles of HTML and CSS to create a website from scratch.
Having some awesome third party themes made it easy to start with someone&rsquo;s awesome template and tweak it to my liking (as seen here).</p>

<p>I&rsquo;ll keep it short for now but I&rsquo;m glad I finally got this monkey off my back.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
