<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Food | Joshua Kalpin's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://kapin.github.io/blog/categories/food/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://kapin.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-03-03T17:09:07-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://kapin.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Joshua Kalpin]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why You Should Do Lunch With Leaders]]></title>
    <link href="http://kapin.github.io/blog/2013/11/21/why-you-should-do-lunch-with-leaders/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-21T22:38:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://kapin.github.io/blog/2013/11/21/why-you-should-do-lunch-with-leaders</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>For the past few months I’ve been interning at <a href="http://lookout.com">Lookout</a> in San Francisco. Besides being a totally badass place to work, there is an awesome tradition that all new hires and interns get to participate in called “Lunch With Leaders.” This weekly event, and associated company provided lunch is an opportunity for new employees and interns to get to know the executive team at the company. </p>

<p>Each lunch usually begins with the executive talking a bit about their background and why they ended up working at the company. From there, it usually turns into a Reddit style AMA where everyone can ask a variety of questions about pretty much everything.</p>

<h1 id="why-this-is-awesome">Why This is Awesome</h1>

<p>Lunch with Leaders helps break down that sometimes mythical barrier that separates employees from the higher ups at larger companies. Since Lookout has grown to what most would call a decent sized company (200+ employees), there is usually not too much interaction between someone like me (an intern) and the VP of Engineering due to general team autonomy. </p>

<p>The other thing that Lunch With Leaders takes advantage of is the connection between people and food. People generally like food and when you share food with people, it creates a bit of a bond. Doing this event at any other time would not have the same effect that it currently does.</p>

<h1 id="why-your-company-should-do-it">Why Your Company Should Do it</h1>

<p>So this all sounds awesome, but why should your company hold a Lunch With Leaders type of event? From personal experience, I can say that I’ve never felt such a connection to the fabric of the company before. Every single lunch I’ve heard a different reason why someone believes the company can succeed. I’ve also gained amazing insight into the thought process behind the various directions that company is heading currently and in the future. Lastly, it has shown a non-business side to the executive team of the company. Without this event, I’d never know that our CEO went to high school with Reel Big Fish or know additional insight into the wine industry from our CFO.</p>

<p>All in all, I can say that Lunch With Leaders has been one of the highest points of my internship this term. It’s inspired me to be a better person, engineer and to think a bit differently when it comes to the software industry. If that isn’t reason enough to give it a try at your company, I don’t know what is.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
